Speaker: The Goods Project is about
building better household appliances.
We wanna build desirable, functional,
and really fit-for-purpose goods.
The Gammoni community, Nic and
Tamena and the Homeland School
Company reached out and they said,
"We wanna get our young people on
really awesome beds, and we wanna
put a washing machine in the school."
We know that beds get dirty,
um, accidents happen on beds.
If people get bedbugs and scabies
and that, uh, sore isn't treated,
uh, that strep A goes through
the bloodstream into the heart.
Unfortunately, uh, young people in
particular in these communities have
higher rates of rheumatic heart disease.
This is something that's completely
preventable through, uh, having access
to really appropriate health hardware,
like a bed, like a washing machine
Speaker 5: Nic show us how to put
all things together, so yeah, we
know how to pack it and unpack.
Speaker: Here go in this one?
Speaker 5: Yeah.
Speaker 6: It was,
like, so fun.
I was making my own bed.
Speaker: Just push it.
They're fully flat packable.
They're made from plastic waste,
things like bottle caps, milk
bottles, jerry cans, water tanks.
You just shred it down, like makes a pulp.
Yep.
And then you heat it up and press
it, and you can make a panel.
The dream for the future is that
the community can actually collect
plastic that's harming the country.
It can be shredded down and stored, and
it can create jobs for young people, but
it also can be a part of the curriculum.
Speaker 2: We had some really good,
uh, conversations around healthy
sleep and healthy lifestyles.
A good night's sleep means the kids are
fresh and ready for school the next day.
Speaker 3: Tested.
Speaker: I think that's a really humbling
thing about sleep is that it's so
important to all of us wherever we are,
and having access to a really awesome
bed is, in my belief, a human right.
This is
Speaker 7: the bed.
It's comfortable.
Bringing it out this way.
Yeah.
During the day, no
Speaker: dogs.
We've delivered hundreds of these beds
around the country, in particular in the
central desert, but this is the biggest
bed build we've done in one community.
We did our biggest bed
build ever of over 40 beds.
And when they do get dirty, you can bring
the beds to school, you can wash them,
you can hang them out to dry, and then
you can sleep on them again that night.
I
Speaker 6: sleep comfortably.
My dad was sleeping comfortable too.
Speaker 2: This is a great project, and
it will definitely have lasting effects
on the students and families out here.
Speaker 5: Yo, I want to say thank
you to Good Son Country and Namaleia.
Speaker 3: Yay.
Speaker 5: Bedding is good